<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Grafana Blog</title>
  <subtitle>Blog posts on Grafana, Metrics, Graphite, Monitoring, Build measure learn</subtitle>
  <id>http://grafana.org/blog</id>
  <link href="http://grafana.org/blog"/>
  <link href="http://grafana.org/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-10-28T01:00:00+01:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Grafana</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 2.5 Released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/10/28/Grafana-2-5-Released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/10/28/Grafana-2-5-Released.html</id>
    <published>2015-10-28T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2015-10-28T15:56:57+01:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="release-highlights"&gt;Release highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img class="no-shadow" src="/assets/img/blog/grafana_2_5_graphic.png" alt="New Time picker"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class="text-center"&gt;
  &lt;a class="button primary radius" href="/download"&gt;Download Grafana 2.5 now&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an exciting release, and we want to share some of the highlights. The release includes many
fixes and enhancements to all areas of Grafana, like new Data Sources, a new and improved timepicker,
user invites, panel resize handles and improved InfluxDB and OpenTSDB support, LDAP improvements, Graph
panel units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-time-range-controls"&gt;New time range controls&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/timepicker.png" alt="New Time picker"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A new timepicker with room for more quick ranges as well as new types of relative ranges, like &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Today&lt;/code&gt;,
&lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;The day so far&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;This day last week&lt;/code&gt;. Also an improved time &amp;amp; calendar picker that now works
correctly in UTC mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="elasticsearch"&gt;Elasticsearch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/elasticsearch_metrics_ex1.png" alt="Elasticsearch example"&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release brings a fully featured query editor for Elasticsearch. You will now be able to visualize
logs or any kind of data stored in Elasticserarch. The query editor allows you to build both simple
and complex queries for logs or metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compute metrics from your documents, supported Elasticsearch aggregations:

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Count, Avg, Min, Max, Sum&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Percentiles, Std Dev, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group by multiple terms or filters

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specify group by options like Top 5 based on Avg @value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auto completion for field names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Query only relevant indices based on time pattern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alias patterns for short readable series names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try the new Elasticsearch query editor on the &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org/dashboard/db/elasticsearch-metrics"&gt;play.grafana.org&lt;/a&gt; site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="cloudwatch"&gt;CloudWatch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/cloudwatch.png" alt="Cloudwatch editor"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.5 ships with a new CloudWatch datasource that will allow you to query and visualize CloudWatch
metrics directly from Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rich editor with auto completion for metric names, namespaces and dimensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Templating queries for generic dashboards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alias patterns for short readable series names&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="prometheus"&gt;Prometheus&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/prometheus_editor.png" alt="Prometheus editor"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.5 ships with a new Prometheus datasource that will allow you to query and visualize data
stored in Prometheus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="mix-different-data-sources"&gt;Mix different data sources&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/mixed_data.png" alt="Mix data sources in the same dashboard or in the same graph!"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In previous releases you have been able to mix different data sources on the same dashboard. In v2.5 you
will be able to mix them on the same graph! You can enable this by selecting the built in &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;-- Mixed --&lt;/code&gt; data source.
When selected this will allow you to specify data source on a per query basis. This will, for example, allow you
to plot metrics from different Graphite servers on the same Graph or plot data from Elasticsearch alongside
data from Prometheus. Mixing different data sources on the same graph works for any data source, even custom ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="panel-resize-handles"&gt;Panel Resize handles&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/panel_resize.gif" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This release adds resize handles to the the bottom right corners of panels making is easy to resize both width and height.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="user-invites"&gt;User invites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/features/org_invite.png" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This version also brings some new features for user management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Organization admins can now invite new users (via email or manually via invite link)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Users can signup using invite link and get automatically added to invited organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;User signup workflow can (if enabled) contain an email verification step.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/issues/2353"&gt;#2353&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="miscellaneous-improvements"&gt;Miscellaneous improvements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InfluxDB query editor now supports math and AS expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;InfluxDB query editor now supports custom group by interval&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Panel drilldown link is easier to reach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LDAP improvements (can now search for group membership if your LDAP server does not support memberOf attribute)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More units for graph and singlestat panel (Length, Volume, Temperature, Pressure, Currency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admin page for all organizations (remove / edit)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id="breaking-changes"&gt;Breaking changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been some changes to the data source plugin API. If you are using a custom plugin check that there is an update for it before you upgrade. Also
the new time picker does not currently support custom quick ranges like the last one did. This will likely be added in a
future release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="changelog"&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a detailed list and link to github issues for everything included in the 2.5 release please
view the &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md"&gt;CHANGELOG.md&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="what-39-s-next-for-grafana"&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next for Grafana?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this release does not excite you then maybe the next one will. Starting next week work on integrating
alerting into Grafana, in a non-intrusive and composable way, will begin. We have already spent a lot of
time discussing this feature with the Grafana user community, done UI mock ups, etc. You can join the
discussion and view mocks ups at &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/issues/2209"&gt;Issue #2209&lt;/a&gt;. Another top
priority will be a table panel and more ways to visualize metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h4 id="download-grafana-2-5-now"&gt;&lt;a href="http://grafana.org/download"&gt;Download Grafana 2.5 now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h4 id="thanks-to-project-sponsors"&gt;Thanks to project sponsors&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.demonware.net"&gt;Demonware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mediamath.com/OpenSource"&gt;Mediamath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 2.1 Released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/08/04/Grafana-2-1-Released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/08/04/Grafana-2-1-Released.html</id>
    <published>2015-08-04T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-20T15:04:36+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="no-shadow" src="/assets/img/blog/new-in-grafana-v2-1.png" alt="what's new in Grafana 2.1"/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve been working to implement many of the features you&amp;rsquo;ve requested since the release of 2.0, and are
excited to announce the release of Grafana 2.1 today. We recommend that all Grafana users upgrade to this release.
Grafana 2.1 brings improvements in three core areas: dashboarding, authentication, and data sources.
As with every Grafana release, there is a whole slew of new features, enhancements, and bug fixes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://grafana.org/download/" target="_blank"&gt;Download Grafana 2.1 now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re excited about this release, and want to share some of the highlights:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id="more-dynamic-dashboards"&gt;More Dynamic Dashboards&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Templating system is one of the most powerful and well-used features of Grafana.
The 2.1 release brings numerous improvements that make dashboards more dynamic than ever before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="multi-value-template-variables"&gt;Multi-Value Template Variables&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A template variable with Multi-Value enabled allows for the selection of multiple values at the same time.
These variables can then be used in any panel to make them more dynamic, and to give you the perfect view of your data.
Multi-Value variables is also enabling the new &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;row repeat&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;panel repeat&lt;/code&gt; feature described below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Multi-Value Select" alt="Multi-Value Select" src="/assets/img/blog/multi-select.gif" /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="repeating-rows-and-panels"&gt;Repeating Rows and Panels&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s now possible to create a Dashboard that automatically adds (or removes) both rows and panels based
on selected variable values. Any row or any panel can be configured to repeat (duplicate itself) based
on a multi-value template variable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Repeating Rows and Panels" alt="Repeating Rows and Panels" src="/assets/img/blog/panel-row-repeat.gif" /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="dashboard-links-amp-navigation"&gt;Dashboard Links &amp;amp; Navigation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support better navigation between dashboards, it&amp;rsquo;s now possible to create custom and dynamic links from individual
panels to appropriate Dashboards. You also have the ability to create flexible top-level links on any
given Dashboard thanks to the new Dashboard navigation bar feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Dashboard Links" alt="Dashboard Links" src="/assets/img/blog/dash_links.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dashboard links can be added under dashboard settings. Either defined as static URLs with a custom icon or as dynamic
dashboard links or dropdowns based on custom dashboard search query. These links appear in the same
row under the top menu where template variables appear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;hr&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="better-local-dashboard-support"&gt;Better local Dashboard support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana can now index Dashboards saved locally as JSON from a given directory. These file based dashboards
will appear in the regular dashboard search along regular DB dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Saving local dashboards back the folder is not supported; this feature is meant for statically generated JSON dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-authentication-options"&gt;New Authentication Options&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New authentication methods add numerous options to manage users, roles and organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="ldap-support"&gt;LDAP support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This highly requested feature now allows your Grafana users to login with their LDAP credentials.
You can also specify mappings between LDAP group memberships and Grafana Organization user roles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="basic-auth-support"&gt;Basic Auth Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now authenticate against the Grafana API utilizing a simple username and password with basic HTTP authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; This can be useful for provisioning and config management systems that need
to utilize the API without having to create an API key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="auth-proxy-support"&gt;Auth Proxy Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can now authenticate utilizing a header (eg. X-Authenticated-User, or X-WEBAUTH-USER)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; this can be useful in situations with reverse proxies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-“read-only-editor”-user-role"&gt;New “Read-only Editor” User Role&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a new User role available in this version of Grafana: “Read-only Editor”. This role behaves just
like the Viewer role does in Grafana 2.0.  That is you can edit graphs and queries but not save dashboards.
The Viewer role has been modified in Grafana 2.1 so that users assigned this role can no longer edit panels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id="data-source-improvements"&gt;Data source Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id="influxdb-0-9-support"&gt;InfluxDB 0.9 Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.1 now comes with full support for InfluxDB 0.9. There is a new query editor designed from scratch
for the new features InfluxDB 0.9 enables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="InfluxDB Editor" alt="InfluxDB Editor" src="/assets/img/blog/influx_09_editor_anim.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="opentsdb-improvements"&gt;OpenTSDB Improvements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana OpenTSDB data source now supports template variable values queries. This means you can create
template variables that fetches the values from OpenTSDB (for example metric names, tag names, or tag values).
The query editor is also enhanced to limiting tags by metric.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; OpenTSDB config option tsd.core.meta.enable_realtime_ts must enabled for OpenTSDB lookup api)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-data-source-kairosdb"&gt;New Data Source: KairosDB&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Cassandra backed time series database KairosDB is now supported in Grafana out of the box. Thank you to
&lt;a href="https://github.com/masaori335" target="_blank"&gt;masaori335&lt;/a&gt; for his hard work in getting it to this point. Also thanks
to &lt;a href="https://github.com/rdettai"&gt;Remi Dettai&lt;/a&gt; for the initial implementation of the KairosDB data source plugin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h2 id="panel-improvements"&gt;Panel Improvements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.1 gives you even more flexibility customizing how individual panels render.
Overriding the colors of specific series using regular expressions, changing how series stack,
and allowing string values will help you better understand your data at a glance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="graph-panel"&gt;Graph Panel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Define series color using regex rule. This is useful when you have templated graphs with series names
that change depending selected template variables. Using a regex style override rule you could
for example make all series that contain the word &lt;strong&gt;CPU&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;red&lt;/code&gt; and assigned to the second y axis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Define series color using regex rule" alt="Define series color using regex rule" src="/assets/img/blog/regex_color_override.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New series style override, negative-y transform and stack groups. Negative y tranform is
very useful if you want to plot a series on the negative y scale without affecting the legend values like min or max or
the values shown in the hover tooltip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Negative-y Transform" alt="Negative-y Transform" src="/assets/img/blog/negative-y.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img title="Negative-y Transform" alt="Negative-y Transform" src="/assets/img/blog/negative-y-form.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="singlestat-panel"&gt;Singlestat Panel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now support string values. Useful for time series database like InfluxDB that supports
string values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="changelog"&gt;Changelog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a detailed list and link to github issues for everything included in the 2.1 release please
view the &lt;a href="&amp;quot;https://github.com/grafana/grafana/blob/master/CHANGELOG.md&amp;quot;"&gt;CHANGELOG.md&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;h3 id="download-grafana-2-1-now"&gt;&lt;a href="http://grafana.org/download"&gt;Download Grafana 2.1 now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id="demo-dashboard-for-grafana-2-1-features"&gt;&lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org/dashboard/db/new-features-in-v2-1"&gt;Demo dashboard for Grafana 2.1 features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="thanks-to-project-sponsors"&gt;Thanks to project sponsors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.demonware.net"&gt;Demonware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mediamath.com/OpenSource"&gt;Mediamath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="subscribe-to-project-updates"&gt;Subscribe to project updates&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;section class="newsletter"&gt;
  &lt;form action="http://grafana.us8.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=2aeb5711db2aececc990be536&amp;amp;id=5585d37ecc" method="post" id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" class="validate" target="_blank"&gt;
    &lt;row class="collapse"&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-10 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="email" value="" name="EMAIL" class="email" id="mce-EMAIL" placeholder="email address"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-2 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="submit" value="Subscribe" name="subscribe" id="mc-embedded-subscribe" class="button postfix"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/row&gt;
  &lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 2.0 Released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/04/20/Grafana-2-Released.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/04/20/Grafana-2-Released.html</id>
    <published>2015-04-20T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-20T15:04:36+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/grafana_2_stable_post.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.0 stable is now released and available for download.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We provide &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;deb&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;rpm&lt;/code&gt; and generic binary tar packages for download as well as APT and YUM
repositories. If your platform is not included, check the &lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/v2.0/project/building_from_source/"&gt;Building from source&lt;/a&gt;
guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="/download"&gt;Download page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/installation/debian/"&gt;Installing on Debian / Ubuntu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/installation/rpm/"&gt;Installing on RPM-based Linux (CentOS, Fedora, OpenSuse, RedHat)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/installation/docker/"&gt;Installing via Docker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/v2.0/installation/migrating_to2/"&gt;Migrating from 1.x to 2.x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-39-s-new-in-grafana-v2-0"&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s New in Grafana v2.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the &lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/guides/whats-new-in-v2/"&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s new In Grafana 2.0&lt;/a&gt; article&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try the updated &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org"&gt;demo site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watch the screencast &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FC13uhFRsVw&amp;amp;list=PLDGkOdUX1Ujo3wHw9-z5Vo12YLqXRjzg2&amp;amp;index=3"&gt;Whats new in Grafana 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="new-grafana-screencast-episodes"&gt;New Grafana screencast episodes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To accompany this release there are now 5 new screencast episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FC13uhFRsVw&amp;amp;list=PLDGkOdUX1Ujo3wHw9-z5Vo12YLqXRjzg2&amp;amp;index=3"&gt;Episode 3 - What&amp;rsquo;s New In Grafana 2.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JY22EBOR9hQ&amp;amp;list=PLDGkOdUX1Ujo3wHw9-z5Vo12YLqXRjzg2&amp;amp;index=4"&gt;Episode 4 - Installation &amp;amp; Configuration on Ubuntu / Debian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=E-gMFv84FE8&amp;amp;index=5&amp;amp;list=PLDGkOdUX1Ujo3wHw9-z5Vo12YLqXRjzg2"&gt;Episode 5 - Installation &amp;amp; Configuration on Redhat / Centos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9ZCMVNxUf6s&amp;amp;index=6&amp;amp;list=PLDGkOdUX1Ujo3wHw9-z5Vo12YLqXRjzg20"&gt;Episode 6 - Adding data sources, users &amp;amp; organizations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=sKNZMtoSHN4&amp;amp;list=PLDGkOdUX1Ujo3wHw9-z5Vo12YLqXRjzg2&amp;amp;index=7"&gt;Episode 7 - Beginners guide to building dashboards&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="thanks-to-project-sponsors"&gt;Thanks to project sponsors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.demonware.net"&gt;Demonware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mediamath.com/OpenSource"&gt;Mediamath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;section class="newsletter"&gt;
  &lt;form action="http://grafana.us8.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=2aeb5711db2aececc990be536&amp;amp;id=5585d37ecc" method="post" id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" class="validate" target="_blank"&gt;
    &lt;row class="collapse"&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-10 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="email" value="" name="EMAIL" class="email" id="mce-EMAIL" placeholder="email address"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-2 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="submit" value="Subscribe" name="subscribe" id="mc-embedded-subscribe" class="button postfix"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/row&gt;
  &lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>March 2015 User Survey</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/04/09/March15-Survery.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/04/09/March15-Survery.html</id>
    <published>2015-04-09T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-20T15:04:36+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://infogr.am/grafana_user_survey_mar2015"&gt;
  &lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/grafana_survey_results800.png" class="no-shadow"&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On March 1st 2015, we asked the Grafana community for a favor. We published a public
survey to solicit feedback on the current state of the product to better understand how
Grafana is being used and to weigh in on some new features we were considering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number and the quality of responses exceeded our expectations. Lots of really useful
feedback on what is missing and what could be better. There were also a lot of
gratifying compliments about how much everyone appreciate Grafana.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://infogr.am/grafana_user_survey_mar2015"&gt;Check out the survey results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 2.0-Beta1 Released</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/03/30/Grafana-2-Beta1.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/03/30/Grafana-2-Beta1.html</id>
    <published>2015-03-30T02:00:00+02:00</published>
    <updated>2015-10-08T08:52:14+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today is an exciting day for the Grafana project, Grafana 2.0-beta1 is released! So much hard work
during the last 5 months has gone in to making this release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.0 comes with its own backend server (written in Go). So upgrading requires a little
more than for previous upgrades. Dashboards are 100% backward compatible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We provide &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;deb&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;rpm&lt;/code&gt; and regular binary tar packages for download. If your platform is not included, check the &lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/v2.0/project/building_from_source/"&gt;Building from source&lt;/a&gt;
guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://grafana.org/download"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/v2.0/installation/"&gt;Installation guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://docs.grafana.org/v2.0/installation/migrating_to2/"&gt;Migrating from 1.x to 2.x&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="what-39-s-new-in-grafana-v2-0"&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s New in Grafana v2.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are so many new features (as well as fixes) to talk about. Below is some of the highlights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="dashboard-snapshot-sharing"&gt;Dashboard Snapshot sharing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dashboard snapshot is an instant way to share an interactive dashboard publicly. When created, we &lt;strong&gt;strip sensitive data&lt;/strong&gt; like queries
(metric, template and annotation) and panel links, leaving only the visible metric data and series names embedded into your dashboard. Dashboard
snapshots can be accessed by anyone who has the link and can reach the URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/dashboard_snapshot_dialog.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id="publish-snapshots"&gt;Publish snapshots&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can publish snapshots to you local instance or to &lt;a href="http://snapshot.raintank.io"&gt;snapshot.raintank.io&lt;/a&gt;. The later is a free service
that is provided by &lt;a href="http://raintank.io"&gt;Raintank&lt;/a&gt; that allows you to publish dashboard snapshots to an external grafana instance.
The same rules still apply, anyone with the link can view it. You can set an expiration time if you want the snapshot to be removed
after a certain time period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dashboard snapshots are really useful when you want to share a whole dashboard or just a panel with an external client who do not
have access to your Grafana instance. Instead of taking a picture you can snapshot the current visible data
and share an interactive dashboard. It can also be used in combination with panel iframe embedding (mentioned below).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="panel-time-overrides-amp-timeshift"&gt;Panel time overrides &amp;amp; timeshift&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Grafana v2.x you can now override the relative time range for individual panels. You can also add a
time shift to individual panels. This allows you to show metrics from different time periods or days
at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/panel_time_override.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You control these overrides in panel editor mode and the new tab &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Time Range&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/time_range_tab.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently you can only override the dashboard time with relative time ranges, not absolute time ranges. When
you zoom or change the dashboard time to a custom absolute time range the panel overrides will be disabled. The
panel relative time override is only active when the dashboard time is also relative. The panel timeshift override
however is always active, even when the dashboard time is absolute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Hide time override info&lt;/code&gt; option allows you to hide the the override info text that is by default shown in the
upper right of a panel when overriden time range options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="panel-iframe-embedding"&gt;Panel IFrame embedding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can embed a single panel on another web page using the panel share dialog. Below you should see an iframe
with a graph panel (taken from dashoard snapshot at &lt;a href="http://snapshot.raintank.io"&gt;snapshot.raintank.io&lt;/a&gt;. Try
hovering or zooming on the panel below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="https://snapshot.raintank.io/dashboard-solo/snapshot/4IKyWYNEQll1B9FXcN3RIgx4M2VGgU8d?panelId=4&amp;fullscreen" width="650" height="300" frameborder="0"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-dashboard-top-header"&gt;New dashboard top header&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class="no-shadow" src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/v2_top_nav_annotated.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Side menu toggle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dashboard title &amp;amp; Search dropdown (also includes access to New dashboard, Import &amp;amp; Playlist)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Star/unstar current dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share current dashboard (Make sure the dashboard is saved before)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save current dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Settings dropdown (dashboard settings, annotations, templating, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; In Grafana v2.0 when you change the title of a dashboard and then save it it will no
longer create a new dashboard. It will just change the name for the current dashboard.
To change name and create a new dashboard use the &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Save As...&lt;/code&gt; menu option&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="new-search-view-amp-starring-dashboards"&gt;New search view &amp;amp; starring dashboards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/dashboard_search.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dashboard search view has received a big UI update and polish. You can now see and filter by which dashboard
you have personally starred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="logarithmic-scale"&gt;Logarithmic scale&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Graph panel now supports 3 logarithmic scales, &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;log base 10&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;log base 32&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;log base 1024&lt;/code&gt;. Logarithmic y-axis
scales are very useful when rendering many series of different order of magnitude on the same scale. For example
latency, network traffic or storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/graph_logbase10_ms.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="dashbord-list-panel"&gt;Dashbord list panel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/dashlist_starred.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is one new panel in Grafana v2.0 and that is the &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Dashboard list&lt;/code&gt; panel. This panel can show the current
signed in user&amp;rsquo;s starred dashboards or dashboards based on a custom search (keyword or tags).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="data-source-proxy-amp-admin-views"&gt;Data Source proxy &amp;amp; admin views&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data sources in Grafana v2.0 are NOT defined in a config file but added through the UI. The backend can also
handle proxying data source metric requests which means that it is a lot easier to get started using Grafana with
Graphite or OpenTSDB without having to spend time with nginx CORS (Cross origin resource sharing) work arounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; For InfluxDB users: The data source proxy feature will
hide database user &amp;amp; password details from the frontend / browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id="relative-time-now-delay"&gt;Relative time now delay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A problem that has plagued many is the fact that graphs tend to dip to zero by the end because metrics for
the last interval has yet to be received by the time series database. You can now work around this by adding
a now delay in &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Dashboard Settings&lt;/code&gt; &amp;gt; &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Time Picker&lt;/code&gt; tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/timepicker_now_delay.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="overwrite-protection"&gt;Overwrite protection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana v2.0 will protect you and your other Grafana users from accidentally overwriting each others changes
to the same dashboard. The same protection also applies if you try to create a new dashboard with a
name that already exists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/overwrite_protection.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="user-preferences"&gt;User preferences&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you open side menu (by clicking on the Grafana icon in the top header) you can access your profile page.
Here you can update your user details, UI Theme and change password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="png-rendering"&gt;PNG rendering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the panel share dialog you now have access to a link that will render the panel to a PNG image.
The panel is rendered on the backend via phantomjs (headless browser). This requires that your metric
data source is accessible from your Grafana server host machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://docs.grafana.org/img/v2/share_dialog_image_highlight.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="user-amp-organization-permissions"&gt;User &amp;amp; Organization permissions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All dashboards and data sources are linked to an organization (not to a user). Users are linked to
Organizations via a role. That role can be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Viewer&lt;/code&gt;: Can only view dashboards, not save / create them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Editor&lt;/code&gt;: Can view, update and create dashboards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Admin&lt;/code&gt;: Everything an Editor can plus edit and add data sources and organization users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt; A &lt;code class="prettyprint"&gt;Viewer&lt;/code&gt; can still view all metrics exposed through a data source, not only
the metrics used in already existing dashboards. That is because there are not
per series permissions in Graphite, InfluxDB or OpenTSDB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are currently no permissions on individual dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="documentation"&gt;Documentation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentation site has been updated. You can still access v1.9 docs via the version selector. The documentation
now live in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/tree/master/docs"&gt;main grafana repository&lt;/a&gt;. If you spot a mistake in
the docs or want to improve it, do not hesitate to submit a PR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The documentation has partly been updated for 2.0, we will continuing to work on docs in the coming days and weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="feedback-and-bug-reports"&gt;Feedback and bug reports&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please report any issues you have on &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/issues"&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="thanks-to-project-sponsors"&gt;Thanks to project sponsors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.demonware.net"&gt;Demonware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mediamath.com/OpenSource"&gt;Mediamath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;section class="newsletter"&gt;
  &lt;form action="http://grafana.us8.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=2aeb5711db2aececc990be536&amp;amp;id=5585d37ecc" method="post" id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" class="validate" target="_blank"&gt;
    &lt;row class="collapse"&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-10 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="email" value="" name="EMAIL" class="email" id="mce-EMAIL" placeholder="email address"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-2 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="submit" value="Subscribe" name="subscribe" id="mc-embedded-subscribe" class="button postfix"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/row&gt;
  &lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Grafana 2.0 Alpha &amp; Preview</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/02/10/Grafana-2-Alpha-and-preview.html"/>
    <id>http://grafana.org/blog/2015/02/10/Grafana-2-Alpha-and-preview.html</id>
    <published>2015-02-10T01:00:00+01:00</published>
    <updated>2015-08-20T15:04:36+02:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Torkel Ödegaard</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As some of you already know, at least those who read the previous blog post &lt;a href="http://grafana.org/blog/2015/01/12/grafana2-the-future-and-raintank.html"&gt;on the future of Grafana&lt;/a&gt;,
we have been working on a backend for the Grafana 2.0 release. A backend is really essential if Grafana is to be able
to expand its capabilities to support alerting, PNG rendering of panels, and of course user managment and authentication.
A backend will also make it easier to install and get started with Grafana as you will no longer need to learn how to
configure nginx or deal with complex CORS issues for Graphite or OpenTSDB. Something that
many new users struggle with when setting up Grafana for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Grafana 2.0 has been long in the making but has seen accelerated progress in the last two months
thanks to my collegues at &lt;a href="http://raintank.io"&gt;Raintank&lt;/a&gt;, where we are working on building a nextgen open source
infrastructure monitoring platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/Grafana2_Preview_1.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="code-amp-docker-image"&gt;Code &amp;amp; Docker image&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grafana 2.0 backend and frontend changes are now public in the &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/tree/develop"&gt;develop&lt;/a&gt;
branch in the main grafana repository on Github. The readme on that branch contains instructions for how to build and run the
new backend. You can also try it using docker with a single line like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight plaintext"&gt;&lt;code&gt;docker run -i -p 3000:3000 grafana/grafana:develop
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no offical binary packages yet as there is still some work that needs
to be done before a beta release can be made. Grafana 2.0 is not ready for
production use yet. If you want to help please checkout out the develop branch
or try the docker image and submit feedback and bug reports on github!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no updated documentation for Grafana 2.0, that is one of the items we will work on
in the run up to a beta release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also try out a preview build on &lt;a href="http://play.grafana.org/v2"&gt;play.grafana.org/v2&lt;/a&gt;, login with
guest/guest or you can signup. If you signup you will be automatically added as a Viewer to the main account.
This preview is automatically updated after each successful commit &amp;amp; build of the develop branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-backend"&gt;The backend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The backend is written in Go and defaults to an embedded sqlite3 database so there is no dependency on
Elasticsearch for dashboards storage. If you are already using InfluxDB or Elasticsearch for dashboard
storage there is an import feature under the account page where you can import your existing dashboards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="panel-rendering"&gt;Panel rendering&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The backend supports rendering any panel to a PNG image, this will enable some slick integration
in the future with services like Slack and Hipchat. When we eventually tackle alerting this feature
should also come in handy as we could provide images of related graphs along with alert notifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently the PNG rendering feature is a just a simple link in the share panel dialog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="user-amp-account-model"&gt;User &amp;amp; Account model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To support SaaS and larger Grafana installations we have added a User and Account model similar to
how Google Analytics has implemented this. Dashboards, data sources, etc are not tied to a specific user
but to an Account, users are linked to accounts with a specific Role (Admin, Editor, Viewer).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To simplify smaller Grafana setups you can configure Grafana to be in a single account mode where new user
signups are automatically assigned to a specific account. And you can also enable anonymous access if you
do not care about authentication or user managment at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently users can signup and login with a specified email/password or via Github or Google OAuth integration.
LDAP integration is in on the roadmap but not implemented yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="ui-changes"&gt;UI Changes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a big challange to modify the existing Grafana UI to accomodate more views like Profile, Account,
Datasources, Admin etc, without sacrificing the clean simple top navigation. We tried many alternatives
of sidebars and collapsable top top navbars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/animated_gifs/grafana2_sidenav_gif1.gif" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above animated gif shows the sidebar we ended up with, as well as the new dashboard search dropdown.
We will continue to refine and polish this solution. For more on the creative process and details
on all the UI mockups and navigation alternatives we explored read this
&lt;a href="https://blog.raintank.io/ux-the-long-road-to-the-shortest-path"&gt;blog post by Matt Toback&lt;/a&gt;. Matt is lead
on customer experiance at &lt;a href="http://raintank.io"&gt;Raintank&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="dashboard-list-panel"&gt;Dashboard list panel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is currently one new panel in Grafana 2.0 that can show the current user&amp;rsquo;s starred dashboards as well
as a list of dashboards based on search query or dashboard tags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="/assets/img/blog/dashlist_panel_1.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a &lt;a href="https://github.com/grafana/grafana/issues/1449"&gt;github issue&lt;/a&gt; for this new panel where feedback
would be greatly appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="standalone-mode"&gt;Standalone mode&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The frontend has been slighly changed to support a standalone mode where it can work mostly like Grafana has
in the past, that is without any backend. This mode is currently broken in the develop branch but will
be made functioning again before release. We belive that many Grafana users value the pure frontend (no backend)
nature of Grafana and we would hate to abandon or dissapoint this user group so we will try to support
a standalone mode and build as long as the interest is high and the complexity of supporting both is acceptable.
But it is likely that long term this standalone mode will be removed, but this is all up to user feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="beta"&gt;Beta&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So stay tuned for a beta sometime early or mid March (if this goes as we hope).
Subscribe to newsletter to get notified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class="newsletter"&gt;
  &lt;form action="http://grafana.us8.list-manage.com/subscribe/post?u=2aeb5711db2aececc990be536&amp;amp;id=5585d37ecc" method="post" id="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" name="mc-embedded-subscribe-form" class="validate" target="_blank"&gt;
    &lt;row class="collapse"&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-10 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="email" value="" name="EMAIL" class="email" id="mce-EMAIL" placeholder="email address"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class="medium-2 columns"&gt;
        &lt;input type="submit" value="Subscribe" name="subscribe" id="mc-embedded-subscribe" class="button postfix"&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/row&gt;
  &lt;/form&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;

&lt;h2 id="thanks-to-project-sponsors"&gt;Thanks to project sponsors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.squarespace.com"&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.dreamhost.com"&gt;Dreamhost&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.demonware.net"&gt;Demonware&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developer.mediamath.com/OpenSource"&gt;Mediamath&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
